## **RAKSHITH B C**

Designation: **Embedded Engineer** Experience: **2 year** 

Mobile No: 7760513512 Email:rakshithbc11@gmail.com

### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

**Loginware Softtec Pvt Ltd**, Bangalore Nov 2021 to till date

**Designation: Embedded Engineer** 

I have a total of 3 years of professional experience, with 2 years(Nov 2021 - till date) focused on embedded product design, development, testing, and programming using languages such as C, Embedded C, and Python. Additionally, I have 1 year of experience in a non-technical role(2019 – 2020).

**Current Employer:** Working as an Embedded Engineer for Loginware Softtec Private Limited, from Nov 2021

#### **OVERVIEW**

- Experience in **Embedded system design**.
- Complete understanding of Embedded software development life cycle with exposureto various micro-controllers and micro-processors.
- Having knowledge on cross compilation and building the source code for various platforms like Raspberry Pi.
- Wired communication protocols I2C, UART, SPI, RS485, RS232 and Knowledge on CAN.
- Knowledge on IOT platforms like **Ubidots**.
- Flexible to work on LINUX environment.

### **PROJECTS**

**Project 1: Mobile Starter Motor Controller.** 

Microcontroller: ATmega328

**Role:** Software Developer and Hardware Interfacing.

Tools: Embedded C, Arduino.

**Description:** This device is used to control electric motors, sets through mobile phone using GSM technology from remote location. The controller is connected to starter and operating through user mobile. By making call user can turn ON/OFF the Motor. It gives manual ON/OFF intimation.

## **Responsibilities:**

- Microcontroller programming using embedded c and testing.
- Resolving Integration problems and testing.

# Project 2: IIOT CNC MONITORING Microprocessor: Raspberry Pi 400

**Role**: Software Developer

**Tools:** Python3, Raspberry Pi 400, Sqlite3.

**Others:** Linux, Thonny.

**Description:** This project is concerned about collecting about 8 signals from the CNC machines and based on signals pattern extracting information like production, emergency and alarm. And all the information extracted from all the signals will be stored in the local database and then the same information will be pushed to the server. And also creating communication between react application, local database and server using API programming.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Design the code as per the requirements and maintain the coding standards.
- Developing in Linux environment, testing.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

- B.E. 2014-2018 july ,(Mechanical Engineering ) from Dr.SMCE in 2018 July with 68%.
- Government Polytechnic Holenarasipura, 2014 with 59%.
- SSLC from Navodaya High School in 2009 with aggregate of 62%.

### TECHNICAL SKILLSET

**Programming Languages:** C Programming, Embedded C, Python.

**Tools**: Linux, Keil IDE, Turbo C, GCC, Python3.

**Communication Protocols:** Serial communication protocols-> RS485, SPI, UART,

I2C, RS232, Knowledge on CAN protocol.

Microcontrollers: Arduino, Node MCU, 8051.

**Microprocessors:** Raspberry Pi 3, Raspberry Pi 4, Raspberry Pi 400, RPi Pico.

## PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: RAKSHITH B C

**Date of birth:** 18/05/1993

Father's name: CHANDRA MOULY PRASAD D

**Permanent address:** Bittagowdanahalli(V), Mavanur(P), Holenarasipura(T),

Hassan(D).

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is correct to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Bangalore

Date: RAKSHITH B C